oipolloi.com 2018-12-26

# Data, Cookies and Privacy – Oi Polloi

### Data, Cookies and Privacy

Here we have a full explanation of how Oi Polloi handles your privacy and data, including a full list of other organisations we may share your data with.

Most importantly, if you'd like to know more or have any questions we may not have answered, please email us on data@oipolloi.com

### How Oi Polloi Uses Cookies

Cookies are small text files stored on your computer by your web browser to allow websites to remember you from one page to the next. Without cookies you wouldn’t be able to log in to our website, never mind add a tasty piece of clobber to the shopping basket and buy it. Cookies are pretty important and this website wouldn’t work properly without them.

### Changing Your Cookie Settings

You have control over how, if, and when your web browser stores cookies. How you go about changing these cookie settings depends on which browser you are using to access our website. If you need any help with managing your browser’s cookie settings then the super-nerds at [AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) can provide you with all of the information and instruction you’ll need.

As we’ve explained, without cookies our website wouldn’t work properly so if you do adjust your cookie settings there is a chance that you won’t be able to use our website any more. Don’t say we didn’t warn you.

### Oi Polloi’s Privacy Policy

This store is owned and managed by Oi Polloi. You can find our full contact details on our contact page.

This policy covers how Oi Polloi treats personal information collected on this and other websites, including information related to your past use of our website such as previous order details.

Personal information is personally identifiable information about you such as your name, address, email address, phone number and so on, that is not normally publicly available.

This policy does not apply to companies that Oi Polloi does not control, or to any third parties that Oi Polloi does not employ or manage. In particular, this site may have links to external sites that Oi Polloi does not own or control and you should look at each such site’s own privacy policy to see how your personal information is managed by them.

### Information Collection and Use

Oi Polloi collects personal information when you register with Oi Polloi and when you use the Oi Polloi website.

When you register we ask for information such as your name, email address, birth date, gender, post code. Once you register with Oi Polloi and sign in to our services, you are not anonymous to us.

Oi Polloi collects information about your transactions with us.

Oi Polloi automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, Oi Polloi cookie information, and the pages you are browsing.

Oi Polloi uses information for the following general purposes:

  1. To fulfil your requests for products and services.
  2. To improve our services.
  3. To contact you.
  4. To conduct research.
  5. To provide anonymous reporting of customer activity for our management team.

Oi Polloi does not store your credit card, debit card or PayPal account details on its server or systems. Payments are processed by our payment provider WorldPay and it is they who keep this information in order for us to receive your payment and issue any refunds that might be necessary. At no time does Oi Polloi have access to your credit card details.

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

Oi Polloi does not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or companies except to provide products or services you’ve requested from our website, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances:

  1. We respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.
  2. We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Oi Polloi’s terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

If Oi Polloi is acquired by or merged with another company, Oi Polloi will notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

Below is a full list of how, and why, we may share data in order to deliver our services.

**Shopify** : Shopify are a cloud based eCommercec platform who operate our online store and point of sale. They are fully safeguarded and have a number of data protection tools in place. Shopify will not share or pass on data. 

If you place an order with Oi Polloi, on our Shopify account we will store invoice details (full name, billing address, shipping address, telephone number - if provided - and email address). These form part of our financial records.

We also store the IP address from which the order was placed, for fraud protection purposes.

Shopify trigger and send all emails related the the processing of an order or return, by placing an order with us you agree to receive these specific emails.

Shopify has servers located in the US and the EU.

**Worldpay and Streamline:  **Worldpay and Streamline are our payment processors. By shopping with Oi Polloi you agree to allow us to pass on your card details (via the web shop or PDQ) to Worldpay. Oi Polloi does not view or store these card details, they are held and processed at all times by Worldpay. 

**Paypal:** If you choose to pay via PayPal on our website, we will store the email address and reference code for that PayPal transaction. Our PayPal account will also store your delivery address and pass it back to your Shopify account.

**Brightpearl:** Brightpearl is our back of house platform. Any details associated with order processing (name, addresses, email address, telephone number) are transferred to Brightpearl's secure servers to allow us to process your order.

**Metapack and DHL:  **We use a tool named Metapack to integrate with DHL's servers to generate shipping labels. Any order that will be shipped by us will have the delivery details temporarily stored on Metapack and DHL's servers for 90 days, at which point the tracking expires.

**Campaign Monitor:** Our email newsletter is supported by a tool named Campaign Monitor. When you agree to receive marketing from Oi Polloi, we will upload and store your name (if given) and your email address to Campaign Monitor. If you choose to unsubscribe from our newsletter, Campaign Monitor will continue to hold those details in a desperate database, although this can be deleted on request. Campaign Monitor will also store the IP address from which you initially signed up for marketing.

Campaign Monitor's servers are located in the US.

**Outlook:** Our internal and external email is handled securely by Microsoft's Outlook. Customer email are stored for future reference. 

It is our internal policy not to hold any data locally, except to process it (for example, if complaining customer lists) at which point we will revert to storing this information within our cloud-based drive as soon as we have finished processing it.

### Your Ability to Edit and Delete Your Account Information and Preferences

You can edit your Oi Polloi account information, including your address and contact details, at any time. You cannot directly change the name, address, contact details and other details of existing orders, but you may be able to change your order details by contacting [mailorder@oipolloi.com](mailto:mailorder@oipolloi.com).

We reserve the right to send you certain communications that we consider to be part of your Oi Polloi account without allowing you to opt-out of receiving them. These will be relevant service announcements and administrative messages. You can remove your Oi Polloi account to stop receiving these messages. Please note that if you place an order with the site, Oi Polloi will keep a permanent record of your details as entered at the time of the order.

For other account information, or for those with an account who have not placed an order, please contact data@oipolloi.com for full disclosure on the data we hold on you, and to request it's removal.

### Confidentiality and Security

We limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products and services to you and to do their jobs.

We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect personal information about you. We also comply fully with the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR). In respect of this site, Oi Polloi Limited is the data controller and Oi Polloi's registration number is Z2071683.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Oi Polloi may update this policy at any time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to your account’s primary email address or by placing a prominent notice on our website. If we choose to send an email, you will receive the email even if you are not subscribed to our email mailing list.

### Questions and Suggestions

If you have questions or suggestions on how Oi Polloi may improve please contact [info@oipolloi.com](mailto:info@oipolloi.com).
